#### Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/jerry-zinkula-78a308a (LinkedIn)

Top Skills
Investments
Asset Management
Portfolio Management

# Jerry Zinkula, CFA

Managing Director Northbrook, Illinois

## Summary

Proven investor with 33 years of fixed income portfolio management and credit experience. Achieved success in multiple leadership roles. Committed to serving others through various non-profit organizations.

I have enjoyed working at Allstate since 1992 and currently lead the private credit program. the years, I have been given leadership opportunities across a variety of asset classes and investment functions, including supervisory roles in leveraged bank loans, public and private investment grade assets, municipal bonds, external managers, hedge funds, strategy and business development, and portfolio management. I am President of Allstate Finance Company LLC. and former Chairman of Allstate's 401(k) Savings Plan Investment Committee.

## Experience

Allstate Investments 28 years 1 month

Managing Director February 2002 - Present (18 years 6 months) Chicago, IL

Assigned to lead/develop various initiatives, including:

- Head of Private Credit: Initiated a start-up middle market direct lending strategy and oversee a \$4+ billion value-add private credit portfolio, consisting of private placements, middle market loans, and Allstate Agent loans.
- Member of Portfolio Management: Responsible for the \$30+ billion property-casualty client portfolios. Also accountable for all external managers and the hedge fund team.
- Head of Municipal Bonds: Allstate's \$39+ billion Municipal Bonds and Rates Group. Assumed position during the financial crisis; co-led a strategy and business development initiative to grow 3rd party assets under management.

- Head of Investment Grade Credit: Allstate's \$40+ billion investment grade credit portfolios, consisting of public and private corporate bonds and asset-backed securities.
- Head of Private Debt: Allstate's \$16+ billion private placement and bank loan portfolios.

Senior Portfolio Manager
July 1992 - January 2002 (9 years 7 months)
Northbrook, IL

#### Key assignments included:

- Initiated a start-up leveraged bank loan asset class, eventually growing assets under management exceeding \$1.5 billion. Had a lead role raising \$750 million in 3rd party debt and equity proceeds for two AIMCO-sponsored collateralized loan obligations "CLOs". Served as Collateral Manager for both funds.
- Developed and led Allstate's investment strategy in 3rd party managed CBO/ CLOs.
- Initiated and helped develop the private asset-backed investment program.
- Portfolio manager for high yield and mezzanine private placements.

Principal Financial Group Senior Analyst - Fixed Income July 1987 - June 1992 (5 years)

- Performed credit underwriting / deal structuring for issuers in the financial services and general services industries.
- Managed the interest rate and currency swap portfolios executed trades and implemented asset/liability management hedging strategies.

Iowa State University
Research And Teaching Assistant
August 1984 - December 1986 (2 years 5 months)
Ames, Iowa, United States

### Education

Augustana College
B.A., Mathematics / Computer Science & Economics

Iowa State University

Master of Science (M.S.), Economics